Allison Hunt: My three minutes hasn't started yet, has it?
لم تبدأ الثلاث دقائق بعد, اليس كذلك ؟
Chris Anderson: No, you can't start the three minutes.
كريس أندرسون: لا، لا تستطيعين بدأ الثلاثة دقائق.
Reset the three minutes, that's just not fair.
أعد بداية الثلاث دقائق، هذا ليس عدلاً.
AH: Oh my God, it's harsh up here.
أليسون هنت: يا إلهي، الأمر صعب هنا.
I mean I'm nervous enough as it is.
أعني ، أنني متوترة بما يكفي .
But I am not as nervous as I was five weeks ago.
ولكنني لست متوترة مثلما كنت منذ خمسة أسابيع
Five weeks ago I had total hip replacement surgery.
منذ خمسة أسابيع، كانت لدي عملية جراحية لاستبدال مفصل الورك كله
Do you know that surgery?
هل تعرفون تلك الجراحة ؟
Electric saw, power drill, totally disgusting
يستخدم فيها منشار كهربائي و حفار , مقرفة بالمرة.
unless you're David Bolinsky, in which case it's all truth and beauty.
إلا إذا كنت ديفيد بولينسكي ، سيكون الأمر كله الحقيقة والجمال .
Sure David, if it's not your hip, it's truth and beauty.
بالطبع، ديفيد، أنه ليس وركك، أنها الحقيقة والجمال.
Anyway, I did have a really big epiphany around the situation,
على أى حال, لقد أدركت شيء مشوق عن هذا الموقف
so Chris invited me to tell you about it.
ولذا دعاني كريس لأخبركم عنه
But first you need to know two things about me.
ولكن أولاَ سأخبركم بشيئين عني.
Just two things.
شيئان فقط.
I'm Canadian, and I'm the youngest of seven kids.
أنا كندية, و أنا أصغر أخواني السبعة.
Now, in Canada, we have that great healthcare system.
في كندا لدينا نظام ممتاز للعناية الصحية.
That means we get our new hips for free.
و هذا يعني أننا نحصل على تلك الجراحة مجاناَ
And being the youngest of seven,
وكوني الأخت الأصغر,
I have never been at the front of the line for anything. OK?
لم أكن أبداَ في مقدمة الصف. حسناً ؟
So my hip had been hurting me for years.
كان مفصل الورك يؤلمني منذ سنوات.
I finally went to the doctor, which was free.
و أخيراَ ذهبت إلي طبيب, والعلاج مجاناً.
And she referred me to an orthopedic surgeon, also free.
وأحالتني إلي جراح العظام, والذي كان العلاج لديه مجاناً أيضًا.
Finally got to see him after 10 months of waiting -- almost a year.
و أستطعت أخيراَ مقابلته بعد 10 شهور من الإنتظار -- تكاد تكون سنة
That is what free gets you.
هذا هو ما تحصل عليه مقابل الرعاية المجانية
I met the surgeon, and he took some free X-rays,
قابلت الجراح, و أخذ بعض الصور بالأشعة السينية مجاناً
and I got a good look at them. And you know,
وحدقت فيهم بشدة، تعرفون،
even I could tell my hip was bad,
رغماً عن إخباري لهم بأن مفصل الورك كان في حالة سيئة
and I actually work in marketing.
وفي الواقع أعمل في التسويق.
So he said, "Allison, we've got to get you on the table.
فقال "أليسون, سنقوم بعلاجك.
I'm going to replace your hip -- it's about an 18-month wait."
وسأقوم باستبدال مفصل الورك -- سيتطلب الأمر 18 شهراً من الانتظار.
18 more months.
18 شهراً آخرى.
I'd already waited 10 months, and I had to wait 18 more months.
لقد انتظرت عشر شهور وفي الانتظار 18 شهراً آخرى.
You know, it's such a long wait that I actually
لقد انتظرت كثيراً حتى أنني
started to even think about it in terms of TEDs.
بدأت التفكير بالأمر في ما يتعلق بمؤتمرات تيد.
I wouldn't have my new hip for this TED.
لن أستطيع إستبدال مفصل الورك لمؤتمر تيد هذا،
I wouldn't have my new hip for TEDGlobal in Africa.
لن أستطيع إستبدال مفصل الورك ل تيد جلوبال في أفريقيا،
I would not have my new hip for TED2008.
لن أستطيع إستبدال مفصل الورك ل تيد 2008.
I would still be on my bad hip. That was so disappointing.
سأظل بهذا المفصل الذي يؤلمني. كان شيئاً محبطاً.
So, I left his office and I was walking through the hospital,
فغادرت مكتبه وكنت أتمشى في المستشفى.
and that's when I had my epiphany.
وهنا جاءني الإلهام.
This youngest of seven had to get herself to the front of the line.
تلك الأخت الصغرى عليها أن تتقدم الصف.
Oh yeah.
ذلك هو.
Can I tell you how un-Canadian that is?
هل يمكن أن أخبركم كيف أن ذلك لم يكن تفكيراً كندياً ؟
We do not think that way.
نحن لا نفكر بتلك الطريقة.
We don't talk about it. It's not even a consideration.
نحن لا نتكلم عن الأمر. حتى إنه ليس مجال تفكير .
In fact, when we're traveling abroad, it's how we identify fellow Canadians.
في الحقيقة، عندما نسافر إلى الخارج، ها هي الطريقة التي نتعرف بها على الكنديين مثلنا.
"After you." "Oh, no, no. After you."
بعد مرورك." أوه، لا، لا. بعد مرورك."
Hey, are you from Canada? "Oh, me too! Hi!"
أها، هل أنت من كندا؟ وأنا أيضًا .. مرحباً!
"Great! Excellent!"
"عظيم ! رائع !"
So no, suddenly I wasn't averse to butting any geezer off the list.
إذاً ، فجأة لم أكن سلبية لأتخلى عن دوري في القائمة.
Some 70-year-old who wanted his new hip
بعض مَن بلغ عمرهم 70 عاماً يريدون استبدال مفصل الورك
so he could be back golfing, or gardening.
ليستطيع أن يلعب الجولف أو يروي الحديقة
No, no. Front of the line.
لا لا .. كنتُ في مقدمة الصف هذه المرة.
So by now I was walking the lobby, and of course, that hurt,
لذا فأنا الآن أمشي في البهو وبالطبع هذا مؤلم،
because of my hip, and I kind of needed a sign.
بسبب مفصل وركي. و أحتجت لعلامة.
And I saw a sign.
ورأيت علامة.
In the window of the hospital's tiny gift shop there was a sign
على نافذة لمحل هدايا صغير في المستشفى مكتوب عليها
that said, "Volunteers Needed." Hmm.
"مطلوب متطوعين". هممم.
Well, they signed me up immediately.
حسناً. قبلوني في الحال.
No reference checks. None of the usual background stuff, no.
لم يتأكدوا من بياناتي ، لا شئ من متعلقات تاريخي، لا شئ.
They were desperate for volunteers
كانوا في حاجة شديدة إلى متطوعين
because the average age of the volunteer at the hospital gift shop was 75.
لأن متوسط الأعمار في محل الهدايا في المستشفى كان 75.
Yeah. They needed some young blood.
نعم .. يحتاجون إلى دماء شابة .
So, next thing you know, I had my bright blue volunteer vest,
ثم , كان لدي سترة المتطوعين ذات اللون الأزرق الفاتح
I had my photo ID, and I was fully trained by my 89-year-old boss.
وكان لدي إثبات الهوية. ودربني مديري الذي يبلغ 89 عاماً بشكل كامل
I worked alone.
عملت وحدي.
Every Friday morning I was at the gift shop.
أعمل كل جمعة صباحاً في محل الهدايا.
While ringing in hospital staff's Tic Tacs,
بينما أبيع الحلوى للعاملين في المستشفى
I'd casually ask, "What do you do?"
يتم سؤالي بلباقة: ماذا تعملين ؟
Then I'd tell them, "Well, I'm getting my hip replaced -- in 18 months.
أجيبهم "سوف يتم استبدال مفصل وركي بعد 18 شهراً.
It's gonna be so great when the pain stops. Ow!"
عندما يزول الألم سيكون شعوراً رائعاً . آه"
All the staff got to know the plucky, young volunteer.
أصبح جميع طاقم العمل في المستشفى يعرف المتطوعة الصغيرة الشجاعة .
My next surgeon's appointment was, coincidentally,
كان موعدي القادم مع الجراح، بالصدفة،
right after a shift at the gift shop.
بعد نوبة العمل في محل الهدايا.
So, naturally, I had my vest and my identification.
لذا فمن الطبيعي أن معي سترتي وهويتي.
I draped them casually over the chair in the doctor's office.
وألقيتهم على الكرسي في مكتب الطبيب.
And you know, when he walked in,
وتعرفون ، عندما دخل،
I could just tell that he saw them.
ورأى السترة والهوية.
Moments later, I had a surgery date just weeks away,
حدد لي موعد الجراحة بعد عدة أسابيع.
and a big fat prescription for Percocet.
وكتب لي العديد من الأدوية المسكنة.
Now, word on the street was that it was actually
الآن، عبارة في الشارع كانت في الواقع
my volunteering that got me to the front of the line.
أن عملي التطوعي في الواقع هو الذي جعلني في مقدمة الصف
And, you know, I'm not even ashamed of that.
وتعرفون ، لست محرجة من هذا
Two reasons.
لسببين:
First of all, I am going to take such good care of this new hip.
أولهما: لأني سأقوم بالعناية الجيدة لذلك المفصل.
But also I intend to stick with the volunteering,
وأيضًا: لأني سأستمر في العمل التطوعي.
which actually leads me to the biggest epiphany of them all.
والذي قادني-في الحقيقة- إلى هذه الفكرة الرائعة.
Even when a Canadian cheats the system,
حتى عندما يحتال الكنديون على النظام،
they do it in a way that benefits society.
يفعلون ذلك بطريقة تفيد المجتمع.